Nicholas Kammer, CPA

Estero, FL | kammer@gmail.com | Github: https://github.com/ScroogesMoneybin | Website: NAEK2.com

SUMMARY

Detail-oriented researcher/programmer with experience in financial and investment assets, management, investment banking, mergers & acquisitions, valuations, data analysis. Interested in programming, data science, and finance.

Computer/Data Analytics programming experience in Javascript, ReactJS, NodeJS, Solidity, Python, R, and Tableau.

EDUCATION

MIT

MicroMasters program in Statistics and Data Science - Online

University of Pennsylvania 2019 - 2021 Master of Arts in Near Eastern Languages & Civilizations GPA 4.00/4.00

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

May 2004 Master of Science in Accountancy GPA:3.97/4.00

Awards: Phi Kappa Phi

Brown University May 2002 Bachelor's degrees in Mathematics, Mathematical-Economics, and Egyptology GPA: 3.81/4.00

Awards: Magna cum Laude Phi Beta Kappa

WORK EXPERIENCE

Owner and Website Developer

2021 - Present

Acceptionally.com

- Online e-commerce site storefront for Nancy's Boutique
 - o Nancy's Boutique is an online multi-platform retail storefront, selling clothing and household items
 - o Nancy's Boutique also distributes through Amazon, eBay, and Facebook Marketplace in addition to Acceptionally.com
- Built with ReactJS site using Redux and Redux Saga on the front-end and utilizes a Netlify serverless functions for deployment
- Processes payments through Stripe Payment Element
- Incorporates Google Firebase and Firestore database
- Includes Progressive Web App (PWA) functionality

2021 - 2022 **Professor**

Ave Maria University

- Professor of Accounting
 - Taught Managerial Accounting
 - Oversaw student projects designing their hypothetical businesses and building Master Budgets
 - o Created PowerPoint presentations for each topic covered and posted them to Canvas website for easy
 - Assisted AMU's career services in networking with local businesses to expand job opportunities for graduates
 - Advised Business School administration on enhancing the undergraduate data analytics program
 - Advised about the appropriate programming tools and languages to emphasize to improve student job placement
 - Researched opportunities to expand in-class learning tools from Tableau
 - Utilized Microsoft Teams to tutor students who could not attend regular in-person meetings or tutoring

- Professor of Mathematics
 - o Taught College Algebra and Calculus for over 150 students at a time
 - Advised students on outside classes (such as computer programming) to give themselves the best career opportunities
 - Created PowerPoint presentations for each topic covered and posted them to Canvas website for easy access
 - o Held lengthy sessions outside office hours and class for tutoring and make-up quizzes and exams
 - o Utilized Microsoft Teams to tutor students who could not attend regular in-person meetings or tutoring

Private Investment Analyst and Trader

2017 – Present

- Managed portfolio of stock and option trades to maximize profits
- Evaluated investment vehicles with emphasis on growth opportunities
- Utilized databases and chart analysis to analyze investment data to select best opportunities
- Manage private trust assets for the benefit of beneficiaries
- Researched new opportunities, including:
 - o Private company angel investments for clients
 - o Advised on the potential of developing exotic asset opportunities for clients

Organizer and Manager of a 2016 Presidential Primary campaign for Illinois

2015 - 2016

- A signed NDA heavily restricts certain details that can be discussed here
- Organized and managed operations and budget as well as 108 volunteers and staff for the entire state of Illinois for a major Presidential candidate in the 2015 2016 primary election
 - Illinois requires direct election of political convention delegates for both Democratic and Republican Presidential Primary candidates for each of the 18 congressional districts, requiring the recruitment of individuals and petition signature collection for them for each Congressional District
 - Worked with state Chairman and national leadership on major plans and decisions throughout the campaign
 - o Personally responsible for most day-to-day operations
- Recruited endorsements from public officials
- Recruited and vetted the campaign's Illinois attorney
- Networked with state organizations to identify potential delegates, volunteers, and donors
 - o Recruited and vetted delegate candidates from across the 18 congressional districts based on their past experiences, social media activity, community involvement, and motivation to participate
 - o Selected appropriate candidates and divided them into delegate slates
 - o Prepared and distributed delegate petitions for each district
 - Oversaw the signature collection process, staying in contact and obtaining regular updates about the progress in each district
 - Deployed additional resources to assist in areas where signature collection was lagging behind schedule
 - Completed the process of signature collection with over twice the number of required signatures for each district
- Utilized campaign's proprietary database to maintain progress toward goals
- Worked with the campaign lawyer and staff to compile completed petitions for official filing with State Board of Elections
- Networked to find campaign donors and compiled list of potential major donors for fundraising events and phone calls from important surrogates
- Assisted with organization and execution of several fundraisers
- Coordinated with our volunteers and delegates to find and set up office spaces throughout the state for phone banking and preparing mailers
- In final months of campaign, worked with staffers sent by national campaign into Illinois ahead of the Super Tuesday II push
- Worked with national campaign schedulers and staffers to plan campaign stops for national candidate and surrogates
 - Chose cities and venues to maximize voter interaction with candidate and surrogates based on knowledge
 of state voting trends along with campaign data and internal polling for maximum electoral benefit

- o Helped chose venues that would best match expected crowd turnout at each location to allow enough capacity but also avoid any negative optics of empty space
- o Helped plan candidate's route for the plane trip across the state, including determining which airports had runways that were long enough and rated for the weight of the plane
- Publicized campaign events through local media

NAEK2, LLC

Valuation Consultant 2008 – 2017

- Worked as a consultant, analyzing start-up companies early in development, especially at the Research Park connected with the University of Illinois' entrepreneur incubator
- Prepared financial statements and projections for the purposes of strategic planning, presentations to awards committees, and recruitment of potential investors
- Performed valuations for companies to determine fair valuations in negotiations with investors, utilizing methods such as:
 - Market-based valuation
 - o Discounted cash flow
 - o Closely-held business valuation
 - o Minority ownership discounting

Dresner Partners Investment Bank

2004 - 2008

Analyst

- Worked primarily in Mergers and Acquisitions on the sell side
- Developed valuation models such as NPV, LBO, and market comparables to determine fair value of client companies for sale negotiations
- Recruited businesses as clients on the sell side
- Researched and recruited potential buyers for client companies

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

NAEK2.com

- Personal website
- Contains selection of Javascript, ReactJS, Typescript, and Solidity projects

Launched Private Blockchain Network

- Utilized geth to initialize and launch private blockchain on the Goerli test network of Ethereum
- Created Externally Owned Account
- Initiated mining for the private blockchain

Dispersion Study of Book of the Dead Spells using Tableau

- Utilized Tableau to track and investigate the geospatial and temporal diffusion of spells from the Book of the Dead in Ancient Egypt
- Mapped the sources of every object with Book of the Dead spells by specified criteria using Tableau's geolocation features
- Cross-analyzed the artifacts by time period, location, gender of the owner, and quantity.
- Performed trend analysis through the time periods to see how dispersion developed chronologically

Develop Database of Ancient Egyptian Coffin Texts

- Compiled, digitized, and cleaned over 6,000 lines of data on funerary texts from old, out-of-print research compendiums to allow broader access to researchers
- Joined data from multiple databases into a broader database for more efficient analysis as .csv and Excel files
- On-going process
 - o Current work has been on data from only one time period

 Database will be expanded to include funerary texts from across multiple time periods, including the Pyramid Texts of the Old Kingdom, the Coffin Texts of the Middle Kingdom, and the Book of the Dead from the New Kingdom and Ptolemaic Period

Classification of MNIST Digits and Multi-digits using Python

- Implemented a variety of data science methodologies in Python to study the famous MNIST database and compare methodologies as applied to the database
 - o Neural networks both manually built and utilizing PyTorch
 - Fully Connected Neural Network
 - Convolutional Neural Network
 - o Support Vector Machine for multiclass classification
 - o Softmax regression with gradient descent
- Successfully tuned hyperparameters of convolutional neural network using PyTorch to achieve 98.02% accuracy for test set of multi-digit dataset

PROFESSIONAL CREDENTIALS AND AFFILIATIONS

- Registered CPA
- AICPA member since 2004
- Personal Financial Specialist (PFS)
- CANSLIM investing certification
- Introduction to Blockchain certificate from IBM
- Foundations of Data Science (Professional Certificate) University of California, Berkeley Online

OUTSIDE INTERESTS

Alumni interviewer for Brown University applicants